librarium-online.com 2006-10-23

# Librarium Online - Privacy Policy Statement

**Privacy Statement:**  
Librarium Online is an independent, non-profit organization whose mission is to enable individuals and organizations to establish trusting relationships based on respect for personal identity and information by promoting the use of fair information practices. This privacy statement covers the site www.librarium-online.com. 

  1. What personally identifiable information Librarium Online collects.
  2. What personally identifiable information third parties collect through the Web site.
  3. What organization collects the information. 
  4. How Librarium Online uses the information.
  5. With whom Librarium Online may share user information. 
  6. What choices are available to users regarding collection, use and distribution of the information. 
  7. What types of security procedures are in place to protect the loss, misuse or alteration of information under Librarium Online's control. 
  8. How users can correct any inaccuracies in the information. 

**Information Collection and Use**

_Information Collection_  
Librarium Online is the sole owner of the information collected on Librarium Online.net. Librarium Online collects only information submited by the user via contests, forums, merchandise, banner-ads, mailing lists, etc. However at no point is does this information leave the Librarium Online database.

_Third Party Advertising_  
The ads appearing on this Web site are delivered to users by our Web advertising partners. Information about users’ visit to this site, such as number of times they have viewed an ad (but not user name, address, or other personal information), is used to serve ads to users on this site. 

This privacy statement covers the use of cookies by Librarium Online only and does not cover the use of cookies by any advertisers. 

_Log Files_  
Like most standard Web site servers we use log files. This includes internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, platform type, date/time stamp, and number of clicks to analyze trends, administer the site, track user’s movement in the aggregate, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use. IP addresses, etc. are not linked to personally identifiable information.

_Clear Gifs (Web Beacons/Web Bugs)_  
Some of our Our third party advertising company employs a software technology called clear gifs (a.k.a. Web Beacons/Web Bugs), that help us better manage content on our site by informing us what content is effective. Clear gifs are tiny graphics with a unique identifier, similar in function to cookies, and are used to track the online movements of Web users. The main difference between the two is that clear gifs are invisible on the page and are much smaller, about the size of the period at the end of this sentence. Clear gifs are not tied to users’ personally identifiable information.

**Communications from the Site**

_Newsletter_  
A user subscribes to our newsletter by registering for our website, we ask for contact information such as name and email address. Out of respect for our users privacy we provide a way to opt-out of these communications via the user control panel.

_Customer Service_  
We communicate with users on a regular basis to provide requested services and in regards to issues relating to their account we reply via email, in accordance with the users wishes.

**Sharing**

_Legal Disclaimer_  
Though we make every effort to preserve user privacy, we may need to disclose personal information when required by law wherein we have a good-faith belief that such action is necessary to comply with a current judicial proceeding, a court order or legal process served on our Web site.

_Links_  
This Web site contains links to other sites. Please be aware that we, Librarium Online, are not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our site and to read the privacy statements of each and every Web site that collects personally identifiable information. This privacy statement applies solely to information collected by this Web site. 

_Surveys [ & Contests] _  
Our site requests information from users via surveys or contests. Participation in these surveys or contests is completely voluntary and the user therefore has a choice whether or not to disclose this information. The requested information typically includes contact information (such as name and shipping address), and demographic information (such as zip code). Contact information will be used [shared with the contest [survey] sponsors] to notify the winners and award prizes. Anonymous survey information will be used for purposes of monitoring or improving the use and satisfaction of this site. Users’ personally identifiable information is not shared with third parties unless we give prior notice and choice. Though we may use an intermediary to conduct these surveys or contests, they may not use users’ personally identifiable information for any secondary purposes. 

_Security_  
This Web site takes every precaution to protect our users’ information. When users submit sensitive information via the Web site, their information is protected both online and off-line.

When our registration/order form asks users to enter sensitive information (such as credit card number and/or social security number), that information is encrypted and is protected with the best encryption software in the industry - SSL. While on a secure page, such as our order form, the lock icon on the bottom of Web browsers such as Netscape Navigator and Microsoft Internet Explorer becomes locked, as opposed to un-locked, or open, when users are just ‘surfing’.

_Supplementation of Information_  
In order for this Web site to properly fulfill its obligation to users it is necessary for us to supplement the information we receive with information from 3rd party sources.

_Notification of Changes_  
If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes to this privacy statement, the homepage, and other places we deem appropriate so our users are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it. We will use information in accordance with the privacy policy under which the information was collected. 

With the exception of the pictures/images/sounds/text of the bands, albums, songs, and record labels, all text and images contained herein are owned by and are Copyright © 1995 - 2005 Librarium Online, LLC. Copying and/or reproduction except as noted is denied. If you'd like to link here, copy and/or use any of this material for any purpose, please read our copy and use provisions below. Thank you.

If you would like to reproduce and/or use part of or all of this text in a printed document for educational, non-profit purposes you are welcome to do so, all I ask is that credit be given to me on the same document this information is reproduced, and that none of this text be modified or altered (if you would like to add your own comments feel free to do so by including them in parenthesis and establishing that the comments are not my own.) I do not give permission for any contents herein to be reproduced in whole or in part on another web page or web site (whatever the nature or purpose) or to be reproduced in whole or in part in any publication or collection of widespread circulation, whether offline or online, for whatever purpose. Translations of this page into other languages are not authorized.
